<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Vedic Cricket</string>
    <string name="sample">Squaring of numbers between 50 and 60 Steps (1) Add 25 to the digit in the units place and put it as the left-hand part of the answer. (2) Square the digits in the units place and put it as the right-hand part of the answer. (If it is a single digit then convert it to two digits) Time-Minimum 10 sec Pro 5 sec Questions- Squaring of numbers ending in 5 In 65, the number apart from 5 is 6. After 6 comes 7. So, we multiply 6 by 7 and write down the answer 42. Next, we multiply the last digits, viz. (5 × 5) and write down 25 to the right of 42 and complete our multiplication. Our answer is 4225. The previous examples that we solved were of two-digits each. But the same technique can be extended to numbers of any length. In the current example, we will try to determine the square of a three-digit number – 105. Apart from 5 the digits are 1 and 0, that is, 10. After 10 comes 11. We multiply 10 with 11 and write the answer as 110. We suffix 25 to it and write the final answer as 11025. The square of 105 is 11025. Time-Minimum 15 sec Pro 8 sec Questions- 115 245 Thus, there are two conditions necessary for this multiplication. The first condition is that the last digits should add to 10 and the second condition is that the remaining digits should be the same. we have to multiply 107 by 103. In this case the last digits 7 and 3 add to 10 and the remaining digits are the same. We will obtain the product using the same procedure. • First, we will multiply the number 10 by the number that follows it, 11, and write the answer as 110 • Next, we multiply the right-hand most digits, viz. 7 and 3, and write the answer as 21. The complete answer is 11021 Time-Minimum 15 sec Pro 8 sec Questions- 37*33 53*56 Multiply 654 by 999 • We subtract 1 from 654 and write half the answer as 653. Answer at this stage is 653____ • Now we will be dealing with 653. Subtract each of the digits six, five and three from nine and write them in the answer one by one. • Nine minus six is 3. Nine minus five is 4. Nine minus three is 6. • The answer already obtained was 653 and now we suffix to it the digits 3, 4 and 6. The complete answer is 653346 Time-Minimum 20 sec Pro 10 sec Questions- 578467*999999 574*999 (Multiplying a number with a higher number of nines) (Q) Multiply 45 with 999 There are three nines in the multiplier. However, the multiplicand 45 has only two digits. So we add a zero and convert 45 to 045 and make it a three digit number. After having done so, we can carry on with the procedure explained in Case 1. First we subtract 1 from 045 and write it down as 044. Next, we subtract each of the digits of 044 from 9 and write the answer as 955. The complete answer is 044955. Time-Minimum 15 sec Pro 10 sec Questions- 75*999</string>
</resources>